

Francis Alagbe

Professional Summary

To obtain a position with your company were I can impact my experience and contribute my skills, experience and knowledge towards the growth of your company. Excellent work ethic, teamwork and time management skills. Great skills with MS-office, web development and computers generally. Excellent customer services. Good communication skills, honesty and great friendly attributes. Respect for confidentiality. Ability to adapt to different conditions, Possesses compassion, empathy and very caring. Multi-faceted software developer who is knowledgeable in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. A true team player offering 3 years of experience in the software industry. Seeking the opportunity to provide outstanding, clean code in a collaborative environment.

Work History

Rentease - Software Developer Winnipeg, Manitoba 10/2018 - Current

- Led a team of 5 developers in the analysis and rebuild of software from the ground up through completion.
- Collaborated on all stages of the systems development lifecycle, from requirements gathering to production releases.
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.
- Debugged and modified software components.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Streamlined deployment process by developing continuous integration tools.
- Ensured that bug reports were remedied and all issues were handled in a timely manner.

Market Force Inc - Customer Service Representative Winnipeg, MB 07/2018 - Current

- Recommended products and services aligned with customers' needs and preferences.
- Delivered exceptional customer service by maintaining extensive

Frankalasho@gmail.com 431-997-1317 233 kearney street winnipeg MB R2M 4B5

Skills

- Exceptional time management
- Security expert
- Software development
- Advanced problem solving skills
- Hardware and software installation
- Software testing
- Web development
- Troubleshooting and debugging
- Innovative
- Project management
- Customer service
- Technical writing
- E-commerce background
- JavaScript specialist
- Technical support
- Programming
- Call center
- Data entry
- Quality assurance and control
- Complaint resolution
- Strong client relations
- POS systems expert

Education

2017 University Of Manitoba knowledge of products and services and creating a welcoming environment.

- Applied highly effective selling skills while properly engaging and presenting solutions to customers.
- Set up and explained new membership contracts.
- Assisted customers promptly and politely, in person and via telephone.
- Investigated and resolved customer inquiries and complaints in a timely and empathetic manner.
- Contacted customer to follow up on purchases, suggest new merchandise and inform on promotions and upcoming events.
- Developed reputation as an efficient service provider with high levels of accuracy.

24-7 Intouch - Customer Service Specialist Winnipeg, MB

01/2016 - 08/2018

- Defined and articulated learning outcomes, including measurements, performance metrics and changes to improve student learning.
- Tracked orders and shipments while assisting with other customer service needs.
- Coordinated with the shipping department to get materials sent back to the vendor.
- Entered customer data into the CSC system and communicated service concerns with the order department.
- Followed up with vendors to get materials returned to them.
- Created and reviewed invoices to ensure accuracy while working with customers to answer questions and address payment issues.
- Reviewed customer service issues to drive continuous improvement initiatives.

CBI Home Health - Real Time Analyst

Winnipeg, MB

02/2017 - 05/2018

- Developed workflow solutions by identifying and resolving common issues.
- Produced and analyzed reports to identify inefficiencies.
- Forecasted workload volume to appropriately allocate to staff.
- Received multiple positive reviews which acknowledged dedication to excellent customer service.
- Monitored inbound calls to provide quality customer support.

Canadian Property Stars - Outside Sales Agent

Winnipeg, Manitoba

01/2014 - 03/2014

- Demonstrated products and specific features at customer locations and special events.
- Used a consultative sales approach to understand and meet customer

Computer And Information Science General

2018

Manitoba Institute Of Trades And Technology Winnipeg, MB

Associate of Science: Software Developer

needs.

- Serviced existing accounts on a regular basis to maximize revenue.
- Developed accurate sales forecasts by analyzing sales feedback and wrote reports for senior leadership.
- Monetized dormant leads to increase profits.

Lexington Computers - Personnel Assistant Ikeja, Lagos 01/2013 - 12/2013

- Performed various administrative functions, including filing paperwork, delivering mail, sorting mail, office cleaning and bookkeeping.
- Managed employee exit interviews and paperwork.
- Recruited and screened qualified potential employees.
- Assisted with meetings and presentations within company.
- Delivered friendly assistance with new hires throughout the interviewing and hiring process.
- Maintained and scheduled complex calendars.

MTN Nigeria Communications Limited - Technical Support Specialist Lagos, LA

03/2012 - 12/2013

- Fielded inbound phone calls to deliver effective support and remotely resolve service issues.
- Resolved a diverse range of technical issues across multiple systems and applications.
- Collaborated with supervisors to escalate and address customer inquiries or technical issues.
- Assisted customers in identifying issues and explained solutions to restore service and functionality.
- Utilized tools and resources to identify and resolve issues.
- Managed equipment upgrades, programming adjustments and billing information.
- Recorded and maintained relevant notes for each client and work order.
- Adhered to all company established policies and procedures.

References

Reference Available upon request